## **Zachary Waldowski**

### **Senior Software Engineer**

#### **Profile**

I am a tireless and passionate problem-solver with a decade of experience bringing uncompromising excellence to users. As a technical leader, I advise and elevate team members at all levels, promote internationalization and accessibility, and focus on quality deliverables. I am remembered for "seriously scary" recall of years-past details, pitfalls, and fixes.

#### **Experience**

Senior Solution Architect, Big Nerd Ranch; Atlanta, GA – 2021-Present Providing deep understanding and expertise for clients targeting iPhone, iPad, and Mac. Delivering popular new features while revamping legacy code as a technical lead for a product with 90,000,000 users. Leading the vanguard of best practices and adopting new technology.

Solution Architect, Instructor; Big Nerd Ranch; Atlanta, GA – 2020-2021 Managing client success from planning to implementation and beyond with an emphasis on iPhone and iPad. Collaborating closely with partners and stakeholders to implement pixel perfection. Planning, authoring, and delivering training for SwiftUI and Combine.

Software Developer, Instructor; Big Nerd Ranch; Atlanta, GA – 2016-2020 Building innovative iPhone, iPad, and Mac applications and teaching cohorts of engineers around the world to do the same for their customers. Bringing new products to market. Elevating teams by evaluating and designing frameworks.

Software Developer, Big Nerd Ranch; Atlanta, GA – 2013-2016
Delivery and maintenance of market-leading iPhone apps. Meeting challenging deadlines with agility, collaboration, and foreword thinking.
Leveraging the power of Swift for the iPhone and Mac in the B2B space.

#### **Internships**

Software Developer Intern, Big Nerd Ranch; Atlanta, GA – 2013 Contributing features and bug fixes to new apps on iOS for Fortune 500 clients. Building internal-facing apps and tooling for iOS and web. Building skills in project management and customer relations.

#### **Education**

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA - 2012-2013

Completed credits towards Bachelor of Computer Science. Extended leave of absence.

Coastal Carolina University, Conway, SC – 2010-2012 Dual-enrollment.



# **Details**951 Glenwood Ave SE Unit 2105 Atlanta, GA 30316

+1 (843) 333-6836 zach@waldowski.me waldowski.me

**United States** 

On-site, Hybrid, or Remote

#### **Strengths**

- ▶ iOS Development
- ▶ UIKit, Mac Catalyst
- ► Swift, Objective-C
- ► SwiftUI
- Debugging, maintenance, and performance
- ► Agile project lifecycle
- ► Technical leadership
- Direct collaboration with stakeholders

#### **Hobbies**

Gaming, Cooking, Traveling